cahoot.com 2008-06-15

# security and privacy

We are committed to protecting the privacy of all personal information which we obtain from you when you visit the cahoot website and when you use your cahoot account. Our aim is to safeguard the security and privacy of your personal information whilst providing you with a personalised service that keeps you up-to-date with products and services which meet your preferences and needs. By using the cahoot website, you agree to the collection and use of such information in accordance with the following Privacy Policy and Data Protection Statement.

For information on what we're doing to keep your money safe and what you can do to help see our online security page.

## security

We employ appropriate technical security measures to protect your personal information and ensure that it is not accessed by unauthorised persons. Information storage is on secure computers in a locked information centre and information is encrypted wherever possible. Our security procedures also provide that we may request proof of identification before we will release personal information to you. We undergo periodic reviews of our security policies and procedures to ensure that cahoot systems are secure and protected.

What does 'This page contains both secure and non-secure items' message mean?

This message occurs when the page displays both the secure and non-secure items, such as pictures. You should select 'yes' to view the page. Your financial details with cahoot are completely secure and in no way compromised. 

## privacy

### What information is obtained about you and what do we use the information for? 

  1. #### Cookies

Cookies are small files which are stored on the user's hard drive for the purpose of identifying their computer and preferences. The cahoot system requires this information to operate its banking processes. We also use cookies to obtain general statistical data about users of our website and their interests so that we can improve our website in accordance with user preferences. We may share aggregated demographic data with our business partners in order to provide users with information and offers that best match their interests. 

If you open an account, we will use information gathered via cookies to keep you informed of products and services offered by us or our business partners in which we think you might be interested. 

##### Enabling/Disabling cookies

If you wish to disable cookies on your browser, follow the instructions below and select the disable/reject options instead.

If you do disable cookies, you will not be able to make full use of cahoot's banking service. 

If cookies are disabled on your browser, here are the instructions on how to re-enable them. Please follow the instructions specific to your browser version. 

##### Microsoft Internet Explorer v5

    1. Click on the 'Tools' menu,
    2. Select 'Internet Options...',
    3. Click on the 'Security' tab and choose the 'Custom Level...' button,
    4. Find the 'Cookies' option and enable both types, 'stored...' (Permanent cookies) and 'per session...' (Temporary cookies)
    5. Click OK to confirm

##### Microsoft Internet Explorer v6

    1. Click on the 'Tools' menu,
    2. Select 'Internet Options…',
    3. Click on the 'Privacy' tab and choose the 'Advanced options…' button,
    4. Check the 'Override automatic cookie handling' tick-box, 
    5. Enable the 'First party' cookies by choosing the 'Accept' or 'Prompt' option, 
    6. Enable the 'Third party' cookies by choosing the 'Accept' or 'Prompt' option
    7. Click OK to confirm

##### Netscape Navigator v7

    1. Click on 'Edit' on the menu bar and select 'Preferences...',
    2. Click the 'Security & Privacy' arrow category and select 'Cookies',
    3. In 'Acceptance Policy' at the top, choose the 'Allow cookies based on privacy settings' option
    4. Click OK to confirm
  2. #### Application information

In order to apply for the cahoot account or any other product or service featured on our website, you will be asked to provide certain relevant personal information which we need to process your application request. We will use your information to confirm your identity and maintain your account.

  3. #### Account information

From time to time we may review the use of your account including any transactions you make to enable us to provide the best possible terms and service.

  4. #### Credit reference agencies

In accordance with standard banking practice, if you apply to open an account or increase any credit limit, we may seek a credit reference about you from a credit reference agency to help us check your credit status.

### Who do we disclose your information to?

  1. #### **Credit reference agencies**

In accordance with standard banking practice, if you apply for an account, we will provide certain information about you to a credit reference agency to carry out a credit assessment. If you open an account, we will provide regular details about your use of your account to the credit reference agency. Information held by credit reference agencies is available to other businesses to cross-check to prevent fraud and money laundering, trace debtors and assess credit applications. 

  2. #### **Business partners**

cahoot does not sell, rent or trade your personal information to others. However, cahoot may share your information with other companies in the Abbey National Group and its business partners include third parties who provide us with services to enable us to operate the cahoot website and the cahoot account. We will endeavour to provide your information only to business partners who agree to use such information in a manner which is consistent with this policy.

## joint Applications

Where you and another person wish to open a joint account, each one of you needs to submit your own application details to us so that we know each of you has agreed to your details being used in accordance with this policy. 

## **location**

From time to time, we may need to transfer your personal information outside the European Economic Area where this is necessary to operate your account or provide information to a cahoot business partner. Where we do so we will take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal data receives similar protections as those within the European Economic Area.

## accessing and updating your information

You may request a copy of the information which we have about you at any time by writing to us at cahoot, 3rd Floor Friars House, Manor House Drive, Coventry, CV1 2TE. A fee of £10 will apply.You may inform us at any time that your personal details have changed by filling out the appropriate pages on the change personal details section of the cahoot website. We will change your personal details in accordance with your instructions.

## data protection statement 

In this statement, 'cahoot' means **cahoot** , a division of Abbey National plc. This statement relates to the information you give in the online application form and to any other information which you provide to cahoot or which it holds on you whether or not you become a customer.

**If your application is unsuccessful cahoot may pass your information to Loans.co.uk who may use this information to offer you alternative products and may make an additional search against a credit reference agency. By continuing with your application you are agreeing that we can pass all your information to Loans.co.uk.**

## credit assessment

**cahoot** may use your information for the purposes of determining whether you are eligible to open a cahoot account or to provide or increase any credit and, in particular, to carry out a credit assessment, which may include credit scoring, except for savings or savings and investment applications. **cahoot** may search the files of credit reference agencies which will keep a record of each search and make any other enquiries relating to you that it considers necessary (e.g. from another financial institution). Details about you and the conduct of your **cahoot account** will also be passed to credit reference agencies. An association between joint applicants or between yourself and any named partner/spouse will be created at the credit reference agency. This will link your financial records, each of which will be taken into account in all future applications by either or both of you. If an association already exists then your application will be assessed with reference to these associated records. This situation will continue until one of you successfully files a disassociation at the credit reference agency. 

Before opening your account, cahoot will check your details with fraud prevention agencies and may make searches at credit reference agencies who will supply cahoot with information, including information from the electoral register for the purpose of verifying your identity. Scoring methods may be used to verify your identity. The credit reference agencies will record details of the search whether or not the application proceeds but please note that this is not a credit check and will not be seen or used by lenders to assess your ability to obtain credit. If you give false or inaccurate information and fraud is suspected, cahoot will record this. 

**cahoot** and other organisations may use and search these records to help make decisions about credit and credit related services and insurance including motor, household, credit, life and other insurance proposals and claims for you and members of your household; trace debtors, recover debt, prevent money laundering and fraud, manage accounts and for statistical purposes. 

For further information on the credit reference agencies and fraud prevention agencies that we use, please telephone 0845 602 0319. 

If your application is unsuccessful and you wish to discuss your application further, you can contact **cahoot** via contact us. 

## information sharing

You agree that cahoot may use your information to open and manage your **cahoot account** and to improve the products and services it offers to you and other customers. You confirm that you are entitled to disclose information about any joint applicant or partner/spouse named in the application. 

**cahoot** may give essential information about your account(s) and card(s) to others including other companies in the Abbey National Group, associated companies and business partners where this is necessary for the operation of the account and to people acting as its agents, on the understanding that they will keep the information confidential and secure. If you have cards on this account, transaction details may be given to any payment system under which cahoot issues cards, e.g. Visa, who may transfer the information overseas to process the transactions, for resolution of disputes and for statistical purposes. The information may also be disclosed to regulatory bodies and other organisations so they can check our compliance with regulatory requirements and voluntary codes of practice. **If your application is unsuccessful cahoot may pass your information to Loans.co.uk who may use this information to offer you alternative products.** cahoot may send your personal data to Abbey National Group companies, associated companies or business partners, including to countries outside the European Economic Area, on the understanding that they will keep the information confidential and secure. 

## cahoot marketing

**cahoot does not sell, rent or trade your personal information to others.**

Your information may be shared with other companies in the Abbey National Group, associated companies or business partners to advise you, by post, telephone or other electronic media, of any cahoot-approved products and services that may be of interest to you. When deciding whether to send you details of credit products cahoot may disclose your name and address to a credit reference agency in the future.

From time to time, cahoot may ask you to take part in its customer research, via email or telephone. In particular, cahoot may use your information, including any information about your transactions, to inform you about any products or services in which you may be interested.
